Finding Aid for the David Mcdowell Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
David Mcdowell Papers
undated
1939-1980
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0272
2.1 linear_feet
Scope and Content Note
The papers of David McDowell, editor, were acquired by Speical Collections in 1983. The collection, consisting mostly of incoming correspondence, covers a period of 1939-1980.
While attending St. Andrew's in Sewanee, Vanderbilt, and Kenyon College, McDowell became acquainted with many of the laureates of Southern literature whose letters can be found in this collection. David McDowell strengthened these ties when he served as an editor for several of the writers at Random House and at his own publishing company, McDowell, Obolensky, Inc.
James Agee, Brainard Cheney, Caroline Gordon, Robert Lowell, and William Carlos Williams, all corresponded with McDowell. Members of the Fugitive group of poets, John Crowe Ransom, Allen Tate, and Robert Penn Warren and members of the Agrarians, Cleanth Brooks, Donald Davidson, and Andrew Lytle are also represented in the collection. A large portion of the correspondence and some miscellaneous papers concern McDowell's duties as executor for the James Agee Trust and the dedication of the Agee Library at St. Andrews, an event organized by McDowell. Most of these items are of a legal or perfunctory nature.
Noteworthy items in the David McDowell Papers include letters written by James Agee to his mother and Agee's transcriptions of his dreams for a Dr. Uhr. The poet, Ezra Pound, sent a letter, humorously addressed with the Random House logo and written in an extremely abstract script. Harold Courlander, for whom McDowell was an editor, sent letters, excerpts, and newspaper articles as he prepared a law suit, charging plagiarism, against Alex Haley, the author of Roots.
- Incoming Correspondence. A - L (Box 1)
  - Agee, James. (To Franklin), Feb 1939; 5 Apr 1951; 1 Nov 1951; (To Robert), 9 May, N.D.; ("Dr. Uhr"), 16 Oct, N.D.; ("Dr. Uhr"), 24 Oct, N.D.; ("Dr. Uhr"), N.D.; (To Irvine), N.D.; (To Mother), N.D. (Box 1)
  - Berger. (To Andrew Lytle), N.D. (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Cleanth, 6 Apr 1975 (Box 1)
  - Buckley, William F., Jr, 23 June 1960; 15 Mar 1978; 3 Jan 1980; 12 Feb 1980 (Box 1)
  - Burroughs, Floyd. (To James Agee and Walker Evans), 7 Jan 1937 (Box 1)
  - Cassill, Verlin, 27 Aug 1969; 22 Apr 1973 (Box 1)
  - Cheney, Brainard - 10 Sept 1958; 17 Sept 1958; 19 Apr 1960; 30 June 1960; 10 Oct 1963; 11 Oct 1965; 4 Aug 1966; 14 Sept 1966; 16 June 1967; 10 Sept 1972; 12 Sept 1972; 25 Sept 1972; 28 Sept 1972; 10 May 1973; 18 Mar 1974; 9 Oct 1974; 27 Jan 1975; 16 Feb 1975; 17 Feb 1975; (To Esquire), 11 Mar 1975; 14 Mar 1975; 19 Mar 1975; 21 Mar 1975; 26 Mar 1975; 22 Sept 1975;- 11 Oct 1975; N.D., 1975; (To Alexander Heard), 29 Jan 1976; 3 Feb 1976; 9 June 1976; 19 June 1976; 30 Nov 1976; 3 Sept 1981; 11 Mar 1982; 29 Sept, N.D. (Box 1)
  - Coles, Robert, 5 Jan 1979 (Box 1)
  - Corman, Gene. (To Andrew Lytle), 10 Apr 1961 (Box 1)
  - Courlander, Harold - 10 Dec 1966; 11 Sept 1975; 22 May 1976; 8 June 1976; 20 June 1976; 6 Sept 1976; 12 Oct 1976; 15 Oct 1976; (To Herbert Michelman), 4 Feb 1977; (To Herbert Michelman), 9 Feb 1977; (To Nat Wartels), 9 Feb 1977; 4 Mar 1977; 11 Mar 1977; 16 Mar 1977; 20 Mar 1977; (To Nat Wartels), 23 June 1977; 11 July 1977; 24 July 1977; 29 July 1977; 17 Nov 1977; (To Harvey Shapiro), 27 Nov 1977; 8 Feb 1980; 20 Mar 1980; 24 May 1980; 23 Oct 1980; [1977],N.D.; 9 July, N.D.; 2 Aug, N.D.; 4 Sept, N.D.; 29 Sept, N.D.; N.D.; N.D. (Box 1)
  - Davidson, Donald, 24 Oct 1948; 5 Jan 1949; 10 Jan 1949; 7 Aug 1966; 15 Sept 1966; (To Johnson Reprint Corp.), 15 Sept 1966 (Box 1)
  - Donleavy, Mike, 28 July 1960 (Box 1)
  - Dorothy. (To James Agee), 18 Dec 1929 (Box 1)
  - Dorothy. (To James Agee) (Box 1)
  - Egner, Marilynn. (To Frederick Manfred), 3 Mar 1975 (Box 1)
  - Eliot, Alexander, Aug 1960; 22 Nov 1965 (Box 1)
  - Elliott, George, 28 Aug 1971; 18 June 1972; 28 Mar 1973 (Box 1)
  - Erskine, Albert. (To Peter Taylor), 18 Sept 1957 (Box 1)
  - Estes, Glenn E. (To Harold Courlander), 18 July 1979 (Box 1)
  - Eyster, Warren - 16 Mar 1953; June 1953; 30 Jan 1957; 26 Dec 1957; 17 Jan 1958; 8 July 1960; 22 Aug 1960; 21 Dec 1960; 28 Jan 1961; 18 Feb 1961; 17 May 196.1 15 Apr 1962; 20 July 1962; 13 Apr 1963; 6 Aug 1963; 17 Aug 1963; 25 Nov 1963 29 Nov 1963; 2 Oct 1964; 26 Oct 1964; 17 Nov 1964; 22 Dec 1964; 19 Aug 1966; 1 Feb 1966; 11 Dec 1973; N.D., 1973 (3 letters); (To Dr. Anne Loveland), 13 May 1975; 19 Sept 1975; 22 Dec 1975; 16 Aug 1979; N.D. (7 letters) (Box 1)
  - Fitzgerald, Robert, 29 Sept 1974 (Box 1)
  - Frank, Vera. (To Marvin Feldman), 1 Mar 1961 (Box 1)
  - Gardner, Isabella, 2 Aug 1978; 21 Feb 1979 (Box 1)
  - Garrett, George, 22 Jan 1974; 29 Sept 1974; 14 Feb 1975 (2 letters) (Box 1)
  - Gordon, Caroline, 27 May 1966; 25 Feb 1971; 5 July 1971; 11 Apr 1972; 30 June 1973; 23 Dec 1974; 18 Apr 1975; N.D. (2 letters) (Box 1)
  - Goyen, Bill, 20 Feb 1965; 9 Jan 1972; 20 Mar 1972; 26 Jan, N.D. (Box 1)
  - Gunn Julien, D.H.C, 18 Dec 1959 (Box 1)
  - Hall, Jim, 28 June 1960; 29 July 1960; 29 Aug 1960; 6 Sept 1960; 22 Sept 1960; (To Esquire), 23 Sept 1960; 17 Oct 1960; N.D. (2 letters) (Box 1)
  - Hawkes John, 19 May 1975
  - Jones, Madison, 10 Feb 1977 (Box 1)
  - Kenner, Hugh, 3 Aug 1958; 25 April 1960; 8 June 1960; 14 July 1960; 25 July 1960; 1 Sept 1960; 5 July 1961; 1 Jan 1962; 8 Feb 1962; 8 Mar 1962; 26 May 1963; 10 Aug 1966 (Box 1)
  - Laughlin, James. (To Robert G. Davis), 13 Aug 1966 (Box 1)
  - Le Compte, Edward. (To Ivan Obolensky), 24 Aug 1960 (Box 1)
  - Lohf, Kenneth A. (To William F. Buckley, Jr.), 14 Dec 1979 (Box 1)
  - Long, Maggie. N.D. (2 letters) (Box 1)
  - Lowell, Robert, 9 June 1948; 15 Nov 1948; 23 March 1960; 14 April 1960; 1 Aug 1963; N.D. (2 letters) (Box 1)
  - Lytle, Andrew - 31 Dec 1955; (To Lowe Berger), 17 Jan 1956; (To Lowe Berger), 27 Jan 1956; 13 March 1956; 28 May 1956; 11 June 1956; 4 July 1956; 24 Sept 1956; 12 Oct 1956; 23 Oct 1956; 5 Nov 1956; 25 Nov 1956; 18 Feb 1957; 9 Jan 1960; 8 Feb 1960; 21 Aug 1960; 28 Sept I960; 5 Mar 1961; 27 Mar 1961; 10 April 1961; 27 April 1961; 24 June 1961; (To Henry), 18 July 1961; 5 Sept 1961; 9 Sept 1961; 18 Sept 1961; 28 Sept 1961; 19 Oct 1961; 31 Jan 1962; 23 Mar 1962; 15 May 1962; 12 June 1962; 12 July 1962; 4 Oct 1962; 10 Oct 1962; 4 Feb 1963; 6 Mar 1963; 27 Apr 1963; 19 Mar 1964; 20 Mar 1974; 14 Apr 1974; 8 Oct 1974; 5 Apr 1975; 21 Apr 1975; N.D. (2 letters) (Box 1)
- Incoming Correspondence. M - W (Box 2)
  - McAllister, Mick. (To Frederick Manfred), 26 May 1977 (Box 2)
  - Macauley, Robie, 27 Sept 1959; 10 Dec 1959; 1 Feb 1960; 14 Nov 1961; 5 Oct 1961; 16 May 1965; 15 Nov 1967; 9 Feb 1977; 19 July 1979; 17 Sept 1979 20 Sept 1980; N.D. (7 letters) (Box 2)
  - [McDowell], Martha. (To Edward LeComte), 30 July 1980; (To Warren Eyster), N.D. (1 letter) (Box 2)
  - McMurrin, Trudy. N.D. (1 letter) (Box 2)
  - Madden, David, 23 Jan 1973; 13 Jan 1980; 23 Jan 1980; Thanksgiving Day 1980 (Box 2)
  - Manfred, Frederick - 25 Dec 1937; 14 Mar 1959; 13 June 1960; 16 July 1960; 19 July 1960; 23 July 1960; 11 Aug 1960; 18 Aug 1960; 9 Dec 1960; 17 Jan 1961 14 Feb 1961; 3 Mar 1961; 20 Mar 1961; 21 Mar 1961; 23 Mar 1961; 25 Mar 1961; 5 Apr 1961; 19 Apr 1961; 1 May 1961; 14 June 1961; 18 July 1961; 3 Aug 1961; 28 Aug 1961; 28 Sept 1961; 11 Jan 1962; 3 Feb 1962; 10 Feb 1962; 4 Mar 1962; 28 Mar 1962; 3 Apr.1962; (To Peter Davison), 7 Apr 1962; 2 June 1962; 28 June 1962; 27 Oct 1962; 3 Nov 1962; 29 Nov 1962; (To Walter Trenerry), 14 Jan 1963; 14 Jan 1963; 28 Jan 1963; 1 Feb 1963; 11 Mar 1963; 19 Mar 1963; 5 May 1963; 24 May 1963; 1 July 1963; 21 July 1963; 26 July 1963; 17 Aug 1963; 26 Sept 1963; 27 Oct 1963; 15 Dec 1963; (To John), 15 Mar 1975; 18 Sept 1975; 1 Jan 1976; (To Nat Wartels), 9 Mar 1976; 17 Mar 1976; 16 July 1976; 2 Oct 1976; 19 Nov 1976; (To Herb), 19 Nov 1976; 21 Dec 1976; (To Gordon), 17 Jan 1977; 16 June 1977; 21 Oct 1977; (To Herb), 17 Dec 1977; (To Herb), 25 Dec 1977; 2 Jan 1978; 14 Feb 1978; 18 Feb 1978; 5 Aug 1978; 3 July 1979; 27 Oct 1979; 27 Dec 1979; 14 Feb 1981 (Box 2)
  - Miller, Henry, 21 Oct 1947; 15 Nov 1947 (Box 2)
  - Miller, [Lepska?]. N.D. (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne, 16 Sept 1958; 30 July 1966; 13 Jan 1973 (Box 2)
  - Murray, Ed, 14 Feb 1982 (Box 2)
  - Murray, James. (To Luther Evans), 14 Jan 1953 (Box 2)
  - Neatrour, Henriette, 29 Mar 1977 (Box 2)
  - Owen, Guy, 1 Mar 1972; 10 Apr 1976 (Box 2)
  - Percy, Walker, 20 Feb 1972 (Box 2)
  - Pope, Thomas, 21 Dec 1977 (Box 2)
  - Porter, Katherine Ann, 7 Nov 1975 (Box 2)
  - Pound, Ezra, 24 Dec 1953; 20 Mar 1954 (Box 2)
  - Puzo, Mario. N.D. (Box 2)
  - Ransom, John Crowe. (To Augustus A. Koski) - 28 May 1941; (To James Agee), 24 Dec 1942; 26 Nov 1945; 25 Feb 1950; 5 Feb 1954; 19 Jan 1957; 28 Jan 1957; 6 Aug 1957; 25 Oct 1957; 7 Nov 1957; 3 Feb 1958; 27 Jan 1965; 7 Oct, N.D. (Box 2)
  - Sandburg, Helga, 28 July 1960; 23 Aug 1960; 16 Mar 1961 (Box 2)
  - Schiefer, Butch and Chuck, 19 July 1957 (Box 2)
  - Seagar, Allan, 25 Aug 1960 (Box 2)
  - Shapiro, Harvey. (To Harold Courlander), 3 May 1977 (Box 2)
  - Spencer, Elizabeth, 8 Jan 1968; 28 Mar 1973; 10 July 1973; 22 Aug 1973; 14 Apr 1974; 1 May 1974; 10 July 1974; 18 Dec 1974; 31 Jan, N.D.; 6 Dec, N.D. (Box 2)
  - Stafford, Jean. 5 Feb 1943; 4 Nov 1943; 11 Dec 1944 (Box 2)
  - Starr, William J, 13 Dec 1977 (Box 2)
  - Tate, Allen. (To Brainard Cheney), 3 June 1967; 3 May 1972; 18 May 1972; 7 June 1972; 19 Mar 1973 (Box 2)
  - Taylor, Peter - 25 June 1942; 2 Sept 1945; 10 Dec 1946; 24 Apr 1947; 6 Oct 1958; 25 Nov 1958; 10 Apr 1960; 6 Sept 1960; 7 Mar 1961; 18 July 1961; 20 May 1971; 16 Nov 1981; Dec 1981; N.D.(1 letter) (Box 2)
  - Trenerry, Walter, 9 Mar 1962; (To Frederick Manfred), 1 Nov 1962 (Box 2)
  - Villa, José Garcia. (To Bob King), 23 Jan 1975 (Box 2)
  - Warren, Robert Penn, 25 May 1966; 15 July 1977; 28 July 1977; 24 Sept 1980 (Box 2)
  - Wartels, Nat, 14 Oct 1977 (Box 2)
  - Weaver, Gordon, 16 June 1976 (Box 2)
  - Welty, Eudora, 7 Aug 1951 (Box 2)
  - Western Literature Association. (To Frederick Manfred), 1 June 1977 (Box 2)
  - Willeford, Charles, 9 Apr 1974; 2 Apr, N.D.; N.D. (Box 2)
  - Williams, Flossie, 9 Apr 1953 (Box 2)
  - Williams, William Carlos. (To John Crowe Ransom), 14 Jan 1949; 31 July 1954; (To Madeline McDowell), 17 Aug 1954; 30 May 1955; 10 July 1957; 25 May 1960; 8 July 1960; (To Father Flye), 4 Jan, N.D.; N.D.(2 letters) (Box 2)
  - Wright, Laura Tyler, 12 April 1954 (Box 2)
- Outgoing Correspondence (Box 3)
  - John Crowe Ransom, 1947 Jan 29
  - John Crowe Ransom, 1947 Apr 24
  - John Crowe Ransom; Oct 28, Henry Miller, 1947 Oct 23
  - Andrew Lytle, 1956 Jan 5
  - Andrew Lytle, 1956 Feb 7
  - Andrew Lytle; Mar 21 Andrew Lytle, 1956 Mar 9
  - Robie Macauley; Apr 11, Andrew Lytle, 1956 Apr 3
  - Andrew Lytle; June 20, Andrew Lytle; June 29, Robie Macauley, 1956 June 4
  - Andrew Lytle, 1956 July 10
  - Andrew Lytle, 1956 Sept 28
  - Ann and Robie Macauley; Oct 19, Andrew Lytle, 1956 Oct 8
  - Andrew Lytle; Nov 16, Andrew Lytle, Robie Macauley, 1956 Nov 1
  - Andrew Lytle, Robie Macauley, 1957 Jan 7
  - Warren Eyster, John Crowe Ransom, 1957 Feb 5
  - John Crowe Ransom, 1957 Apr 16
  - John Crowe Ransom; May 14, John Crowe Ransom, 1957 May 2
  - John Crowe Ransom, 1957 June 24
  - Mr. and Mrs. C.R. Schiefer; Aug 22, John Crowe Ransom, 1957 Aug 13
  - John Crowe Ransom; Oct 31, John Crowe Ransom, 1957 Oct 28
  - John Crowe Ransom, 1958 Jan 2
  - Warren Eyster; Feb 17, John Crowe Ransom, 1958 Feb 3
  - Katharine Shattuck, 1958 May 22
  - Warren Eyster, 1958 July 17
  - John Crowe Ransom, 1958 Dec 30
  - Brainard Cheney; July 22, Hugh Kenner, Frederick Manfred; July 24, William Carlos Williams; July 25, Jim Hall; July 26, Peter and Eleanor Taylor, 1960 July 21
  - Warren Eyster; Aug 9, Frederick Manfred; Aug 10, Helga Sandburg; Aug 18, Alex [Eliot?], Warren Eyster, 1960 Aug 8
  - Hugh Kenner, Frederick Manfred, 1960 Sept 6
  - Warren Eyster; Oct 31, Jim Hall, Andrew and Edna Lytle, 1960 Oct 3
  - Frederick Manfred, 1960 Nov 2
  - Warren Eyster, 1960 Dec 17
  - Mike Donleavy(2 letters); Hugh Kenner; Andrew Lytle; Edna Lytle; Andrew and Edna Lytle
  - Morris Levine; Feb 16, Warren Eyster, Frederick Manfred; Feb 20, Peter and Eleanor Taylor; Feb 21, Register of Copyrights, 1961 Feb 14
  - Morris Levine; Mar 3, Warren Eyster, Robie Macauley, Register of Copyrights, Peter Taylor; Mar 16, Eleanor Taylor; Mar 23, Andrew Lytle; Mar 24, Eleanor Taylor, 1961 Mar 2
  - Warren Eyster, Helga Sandburg; Apr 7, Eleanor Taylor; Apr 10, Elizabeth Taylor; Apr 11, Andrew Lytle; Apr 21, Warren Eyster; Apr 26, John J. Fornacca, 1961 Apr 6
  - Frederick Manfred, 1961 May 10
  - Andrew Lytle, 1961 June 2
  - Andrew Lytle; July 28, Peter and Eleanor Taylor; July 29, Frederick Manfred, 1961 July 10
  - Andrew Lytle; Aug 13, Andrew Lytle; Aug 14, Frederick Manfred, 1961 Aug 8
  - Warren Eyster, Andrew Lytle, Frederick Manfred, 1961 Sept 25
  - Warren Eyster; Jan 30, Frederick Manfred, 1962 Jan 8
  - Hugh Kenner; Feb 7, Warren Eyster, Frederick Manfred; Feb 13, Andrew Lytle; Feb 16, John 0. Erickson, Frederick Manfred, 1962 Feb 4
  - Hugh Kenner; Mar 16, Walter Trenerry; Mar 18, Andrew Lytle; Mar 26, Frederick Manfred; Mar 29, Hugh Kenner; Mar 30, Warren Eyster, 1962 Mar 6
  - Andrew Lytle, 1962 Apr 10
  - Frederick Manfred, 1962 May 31
  - Andrew Lytle, 1962 June 3
  - Warren Eyster, Andrew Lytle, 1962 July 5
  - Warren Eyster, 1962 Sept 26
  - Andrew Lytle, 1962 Oct 8
  - Frederick Manfred, 1962 Nov 2
  - Warren Eyster, 1963 Feb 19
  - George Garrett, 1974 Oct 28
  - Robert Fitzgerald, 1978 July 24
  - Robert Penn Warren, 1980 Oct 20
  - Hugh Kenner, undated
- Agee Library. Incoming Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Bennett, J. Jefferson, 22 Feb 1972
  - Carr, Charles, M.D, 23 May 1972
  - Gooch, Jeannie, 22 Oct 1971; 4 Nov 1971; 9 Nov 1971; 18 May 1972; 28 Apr 1977
  - Martin, Father Franklin - 10 June 1968; 8 Nov 1968; 29 Jan 1969; 13 Feb 1969; 20 May 1969; 19 Aug 1971; 18 Oct 1971; (To Walker Evans), 29 Oct 1971; (To Helen Levitt), 29 Oct 1971; (To N.B. Lyons), 8 Nov 1971; 8 Nov 1971; (To Millen Brand), 26 Nov 1971; (To John Snyder), 13 Mar 1972; May 1972; 2 June 1972(2 letters); (To Robert Fitzgerald), 11 July 1972; (To Reverend Girault M. Jones), 14 Sept 1972; 30 Oct 1972; 15 Nov 1972; 19 Jan 1973; 6 Mar 1973; 8 Nov 1978
  - Payne, Billie R, 3 Feb 1969
  - Ryan, Nancy M. (To June Moll), 7 Feb 1972
  - Spencer, Reverend Bonnell, 11 Nov 1953
  - Stitson, Bill, 13 Feb, N.D.
- Agee Library. Outgoing Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Albert Gooch, 1971 Nov 19
  - Rev. Franklin Martin; Jan 18, Prof. William Stott, 1972 Jan 17
  - Dr. J. Jefferson Bennett; Feb 22 Rev. Franklin Martin, 1972 Feb 17
  - Rev. Franklin Martin, 1972 Mar 17
  - Walker Percy, 1972 Apr 17
  - Charles Carr, M.D., Rev. Franklin Martin, Prof. William Stott, 1972 May 26
  - Mrs. Franklin Martin, 1972 June 29
  - Rev. Franklin Martin; July 25, Rev. Franklin Martin, 1972 July 5
  - Mr. Arthur Ben Chitty, Rev. Franklin Martin, 1972 Aug 3
  - Rev. Franklin Martin; Sept 19, Allen Tate, Peter Taylor; Sept 25, Warren Eyster, Marion Montgomery, Guy Owen, Louis D. Rubin, Jr. Charles Willeford; Sept 29, Margaretta Akermark, John Huston, Louis Kronenberger, Dwight Macdonald, 1972 Sept 14
  - Kermit Lansner, John Leonard; Oct 6, Dr. Brinley Rhys; Oct 13, Nat Wartels, 1972 Oct 2
  - Jeannie Gooch, 1972 Nov 28
- James Agee Trust. Incoming Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Agee, Mia. (To Houghton Mifflin), N.D. (Box 1)
  - Aleinikoff, Eugene N. (To Aaron L. Danzig), 27 Dec 1967 (Box 1)
  - Ashley Famous Agency, Inc. (AFA, Inc.). (To Aaron L. Danzig), 1 Dec 1966; (To Aaron L. Danzig), 2 June 1967 (Box 1)
  - Associated Educational Services Corporation. (To Aaron L. Danzig), 2 June 1967; (To Aaron Danzig), 14 June 1967, (2 letters); (To Aaron Danzig), 29 Mar 1968 (Box 1)
  - Brodsky, Bernard, 28 Aug 1967 (Box 1)
  - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation. (To Jack Hutto), 20 Feb 1967; (To Jack Hutto), 24 Feb 1967 (Box 1)
  - Copyright Office, Library of Congress. (To Aaron L. Danzig), 19 Sept 1968 (Box 1)
  - Crowell, Thomas Y., Company, 31 Oct 1968 (Box 1)
  - Danzig, Aaron L. (To Chester Kerr) 8 July 1966; 22 July 1966; 2 Dec 1966; (To John G. Ledes), 2 Dec 1966; (To Peter Owen), 2 Dec 1966; (To Lovell Thompson), 15 Dec 1966; 16 Dec 1966; (To William Ward), 20 Dec 1966; 5 Jan 1967 (2 letters); (To Lovell Thompson), 6 Jan 1967; (To Peter Owen), 13 Jan 1967; (To Peter Owen), 19 Jan 1967; (To Peter Owen: "corrected letter"), 19 Jan 1967; (To William Ward), 19 Jan 1967; 27 Jan 1967; (To Jules Zalon, c/o A.F.A.), 27 Jan 1967; 6 Feb 1967; 6 Mar 1967; (To Viking Press), 6 Mar 1967; (To William Ward), 6 Mar 1967; 20 Mar 1967; (To Chester Kerr), 24 Mar 1967; 24 Mar 1967; (To Cummington Press), 31 Mar 1967; 11 April 1967; 20 April 1967; 3 May 1967; (To Mia Agee), 4 May 1967; 11 May 1967; 5 June 1967; 13 June 1967; (To Jules Zalon), 13 June 1967; (To Harvard Advocate), 15 June 1967; (To Harvard Advocate), 3 Aug 1967; (To Arthur 0. Leff), 3 Aug 1967; (To Arthur 0. Leff), 4 Aug 1967; 11 Aug 1967; 16 Aug 1967; 23 Aug 1967; 6 Sept 1967; 29 Sept 1967; 13 Oct 1967; 25 Oct 1967; (To Lovell Thompson), 2 Nov 1967; 8 Nov 1967; 10 Nov 1967(2 letters); 30 Nov 1967; 5 Dec 1967; 8 Dec 1967; 12 Dec 1967; (To Lovell Thompson), 12 Dec 1967; 19 Dec 1967; (To Harvard Advocate), 20 Dec 1967; 27 Dec 1967(2 letters); 2 Jan 1968; (To Jules Zalon), 5 Jan 1968; 23 Jan 1968; 14 Feb 1968; 4 Mar 1968; 25 Mar 1968; (To Bertram Frank), 26 Mar 1968; 2 Apr 1968; 4 Apr 1968; (To David Harris), 14 May 1968; 14 May 1968; (To Constance Stungo), 24 May 1968; 24 May 1968; 7 June 1968; (To Texas Quarterly), 6 Aug 1968; 6 Aug 1968; 26 Aug 1968(2 letters); (To Peter Smith), 3 Sept 1968; 4 Sept 1968; 9 Sept 1968; 25 Sept 1968(2 letters) 27 Sept 1968; (To Texas Quarterly), 7 Oct 1968; 16 Oct 1968; (To Texas Quarterly), 22 Oct 1968; 17 Dec 1968; 1 May 1972 (Box 1)
  - Esquire. (To Houghton Mifflin), 11 July 1968 (Box 1)
  - F.W. Faxon Company, 21 Dec 1967 (Box 1)
  - Film Heritage, 8 Aug 1967 (Box 1)
  - Fitzgerald, Robert, 25 Mar 1967; 6 Apr 1967; 29 Apr 1967; 30 July 1967; 23 Oct 1967; 9 Nov 1967; 27 Nov 1967; 12 Dec 1967; 10 Jan 1968; 17 May 1968; (To Lovell Thompson), 24 Nov 1968; 24 Nov 1968 (Box 1)
  - Frank, Bertram, see Schwimer. (Box 1)
  - Freeh, Albert G. see Trust Company of New Jersey. (Box 1)
  - Gatlin, Rochelle, 13 Nov 1966; 17 Dec 1966 (Box 1)
  - Globe Book Company. (To John Leeds), 3 Mar 1967 (Box 1)
  - Grosset and Dunlap, Inc. (To Aaron L. Danzig), 23 Dec 1966; (To Aaron L. Danzig), 18 Jan 1967; (To Aaron L. Danzig), 24 Feb 1967; (To Aaron L. Danzig), 2 May 1967; (To Aaron L. Danzig), 26 July 1967; 8 Jan 1969 (Box 1)
  - Harvard Advocate. (To Aaron L. Danzig), 28 July 1967 (Box 1)
  - Holt, Rinehart, and Winston,Inc. (To John Leeds), 4 Nov 1966; (To John Leeds), 21 Nov 1966; (To John Leeds), 14 Dec 1966 (Box 1)
  - Houghton Mifflin - 2 Nov 1966; 1 Dec 1966; 4 May 1967; 30 June 1967; 8 Nov 1967; 28 Nov 1967; 13 Dec 1967; 3 Mar 1968; 26 Apr 1968; 10 May 1968; 17 May 1968; 4 June 1968; 19 July 1968; 13 Sept 1968; (To Aaron L. Danzig), 27 Sept 1968; (To Aaron L. Danzig), 29 Nov 1968; 27 Dec 1968; 31 Dec 1968 (Box 1)
  - Kramer, Victor. (To Father Flye), 27 Jan 1967 (Box 1)
  - Leaf, Paul, 30 Aug 1966 (Box 1)
  - Leff, Arthur 0. (To Aaron L. Danzig), 5 Apr 1967 (Box 1)
  - Mayer, William, 15 Apr 1967; 17 Apr 1967; 6 June 1967; 16 Apr 1968; 19 June 1968; (To Fred Coe and Tad Mosel), 11 July 1968 (Box 2)
  - Mayo, Charles W, 13 Feb 1968 (Box 2)
  - William Morris Agency, 11 Nov 1968 (Box 2)
  - Noble and Noble Publishers, Inc, 10 Oct 1967 (Box 2)
  - Ivan Obolensky, Inc. (To Kenny Withers), 15 Nov 1966 (Box 2)
  - Opera News, 21 Apr 1967 (Box 2)
  - Roberts, Warren. (To Robert Fitzgerald), 3 Jan 1968 (Box 2)
  - Rosenthal, Richard M. see Weissberger and Frosch. (Box 2)
  - Schwimer, McGinnis, Frank, and Schwimer. (To Aaron L. Danzig), 21 July 1966; 26 Feb 1968 (Box 2)
  - Scott, Foresman, and Co. (To Richard M. Rosenthal), 21 April 1967; 11 May 1967; 19 July 1967 (Box 2)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1 Mar 1967 (Box 2)
  - Shulsinger, Rena. (To Cummington Press), 21 Apr 1967 (Box 2)
  - Simmonds, Harvey, 15 May 1968 (Box 2)
  - Smith, Peter. (To Aaron L. Danzig), 6 Sept 1968; (To John Hamilton), 31 Mar 1965 (Box 2)
  - Smith, Roysce, 7 Nov, N.D. (Box 2)
  - Stott, William, 9 Dec 1971 (Box 2)
  - Texas Quarterly. (To Mrs. Agee), 25 July 1968; (To Aaron L. Danzig), 19 Aug 1968; 2 Oct 1968; (To Pat Higgins), 10 Oct 1968; (To Aaron L. Danzig), 10 Oct 1968 (Box 2)
  - Thompson, Lovell, see Houghton Mifflin (Box 1)
  - Trust Company of New Jersey, 16 Dec 1966; 3 Mar 1967 (Box 1)
  - University of Pittsburg Press. (To Mrs. Agee), 14 June 1968 (Box 2)
  - University of Texas, see Texas Quarterly (Box 2)
  - Weissberger and Frosch. (To June Pait, c/o Scott, Foresman, and Co.) 25 Apr 1967; (To Aaron L. Danzig), 26 Apr 1967 (Box 2)
  - Yale University Press. (To Aaron L. Danzig), 19 July 1966 (Box 2)
  - Zalon, Jules D. see Houghton Mifflin Company. (Box 2)
- James Agee Trust. Outgoing Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Rochelle Gatlin; Dec 19, Albert G. Freeh, 1966 Dec 14
  - F.W. Faxon Co.; Jan 19, Mrs. Mia Agee, 1967 Jan 3
  - Aaron L. Danzig, 1967 Feb 9
  - Grosset and Dunlap, Inc.; Mar 2, Aaron L. Danzig; Mar 2, Albert G. Freeh; Mar 3, Charles Scribner's Sons; Mar 23, Robert Fitzgerald, 1967 Mar 1
  - Robert Fitzgerald; Apr 24, Aaron L. Danzig; Apr 24, William Mayer; Apr 24, Opera News., 1967 Apr 21
  - Aaron L. Danzig, 1967 May 29
  - Aaron L. Danzig, 1967 June 13
  - Albert G. Freeh; July 18, Robert Fitzgerald; July 13, Grosset and Dunlap, Inc., 1967 July 13
  - Film Heritage; Aug 15, Albert G. Freeh; Aug 25, Aaron L. Danzig, 1967 Aug 14
  - Noble and Noble Publishers, Inc.; Oct 31, Aaron L. Danzig; Oct 31, Robert Fitzgerald; Oct 31, Lovell Thompson, 1967 Oct 13
  - Robert Fitzgerald; Nov 30, F.W. Faxon Co., 1967 Nov 20
  - Robert Fitzgerald, Dec 8, Aaron L. Danzig; Dec 18, Robert Fitzgerald, 1967 Dec 6
  - Albert G. Freeh, 1968 Jan 25
  - Grosset and Dunlap, Inc.; Feb 7, Scott, Foresman, and Co.; Feb 14, William Mayer, 1968 Feb 7
  - William Mayer, 1968 Mar 11
  - Rev. James Harold Flye; May 15, Exeter; May 17, Harvey Simmonds, 1968 May 15
  - Aaron L. Danzig, June 28, Albert G. Freeh, 1968 June 13
  - Aaron L. Danzig, 1968 July 12
  - University of Pittsburg Press; Aug 28, Albert G. Freeh; Aug 29, Aaron L. Danzig, 1968 Aug 6
  - Aaron L. Danzig, 1968 Sept 27
  - Texas Quarterly, 1968 Oct 15
  - Houghton Mifflin Co., 1968 Dec 25
  - David Harris, c/o Houghton Mifflin Co., [telegram], undated
- James Agee Trust. Copyright and Royalty Agreements (Box 4)
  - Agee, Mia Fritch and the James Agee Trust 1 March 1968 - "Permit Me Voyage"
  - Associated Educational Services Corporation and the James Agee Trust 2 June 1967 - "Boys Will Be Brutes"
  - Associated Educational Services Corporation and the James Agee Trust 2 June 1967 - "Death in the Desert"
  - Associated Educational Services Corporation and the James Agee Trust 2 June 1967 - "They That Sow in Sorrow Shall Reap"
  - Associated Educational Services Corporation and the James Agee Trust 2 June 1967 - "You, Andrew X. Volstead"
  - Certani, Marguerite and the James Agee Trust 26 January 1951 - "Botteghe Oscure" or "The Morning Watch"
  - Grosset and Dunlap, Inc. and Ivan Obolensky, Inc. 21 December 1966 - A Death in the Family, Agee on Film, and Agree on Film Volume 2
  - Houghton Mifflin Company and James Agee and Walker Evans 25 April 1940 - Let Us Now Praise Famous Men
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, Paul Leaf, and the James Agee Trust 1966 - Let Us Now Praise Famous Men [2 drafts]
  - Houghton Mifflin Company and the James Agee Trust 5 February 1965 - The Poems of James Agee, edited by Robert Fitzgerald